The next series of topics will focus on different types of networks, starting with local area networks, or as they are commonly known, LANs.
LANs, by definition, are networks that are generally confined to a single building or even a single area of a building.
LANs share common resources, such as servers, printers, and to an extent, workstations.
One type of LAN, which we actually covered a little bit in the previous topic, is a perimeter network, otherwise known as a DMZ.
A perimeter network holds devices that need to be seen by both the public and private security zones of a network.
These tend to include web servers, email servers, and proxy servers.
In the example we saw earlier, with a firewall on both sides of a perimeter network, that configuration is known as a back-to-back configuration.
Here's another possible configuration for a perimeter network. Notice in this configuration that there is a single firewall, with connections to all three security zones.
This is known as a three-leg perimeter configuration, with each leg connected to a single firewall.
The exam takeaway here is this: know the difference between a back-to-back configuration, which has a firewall on either side of the perimeter network,
and the three-leg perimeter configuration, which utilizes a single firewall.